-- Usagi Drop Episode 08 --
Presented by:
Taka Fansubs
Saionji-sensei.
You should get some rest.
I'm fine.
I mean, if I sleep now, I'm done for.
Come.
Let's get some fresh air.
We're taking our break.
Okay.
See you.
You guys should get a breather too.
If you need me, just call my cell.
We'll finish right before the deadline.
Let's go.
Daikichi!
It's so hot.
Your body's as cold as ice.
If I turn the AC off, the guys will start sweating all over the manuscript.
People's bodies turn cold from stress too, you know.
Yeah?
I wanted to talk to you about that new project you mentioned the other day.
I don't think you should accept it if it'll drop the quality of your current work.
Ma-chan, you're not really physically or mentally strong.
Besides, you're making a good amount already, so there's no need to hound for work.
But...
What?
I may be doing well now, but who knows what'll happen next year?
There'll always be newcomers sprouting up everywhere.
My luck could change in the blink of an eye.
Ma-chan, don't be so negative.
It's not good for your health.
You've got ink on your face again.
Yeah?
Honestly...
Come on, you're a girl.
I'm a manga artist, not a girl!
I'm going back to work!
I'm sorry about that.
Damn it...
I really don't wanna go to work.
Good morning.
Morning.
I said your name earlier.
Sorry, it's just so hot.
Are you trying to cool off?
Yeah.
Shall we make your lunch?
Hey, come and help me.
Okay!
Rin's on summer vacation now.
Every morning we make her lunch together
before she heads off to her summer daycare.
What do you say we visit Grandpa's grave this Saturday?
The Bon Festival's coming up, which is perfect for...
Huh?
You don't wanna go?
Well, the bellflowers haven't bloomed yet.
I think it'll take a little longer.
For now, we'll go buy some at the florist,
and once ours blooms, we can just go back.
Okay.
Although Grandpa would be happy if you brought your own flowers for him.
Right? That's what I thought!
Still, if you visit his grave he'd be more than happy.
He'd be truly happy.
Okay. Let's go.
If Rin weren't here, I doubt I'd be thinking of Grandpa like this.
Rin-chan! Rin-chan!
Kouki-kun!
It's all a mess if you move!
Sorry!
Citrus
Why is your hair so thin anyway?
Dunno!
What is it?
I'll be right back!
Hey, we'll be late!
What's he doing?
Daikichi, how much longer?
Bon Festival Dance
About ten days I think.
I found it!
A cicada shell!
Its shell?
This sure reminds me of when I was young.
I've got a lot in here.
Yuck!
Don't shake it!
We're gonna be late!
Hey!
Look out for cars!
I've been here lots of times.
With Grandpa?
Yeah.
Oh right, Grandma's buried here too.
Grandpa's grandma?
No, my grandma.
You see, my mom is Grandpa and Grandma's daughter.
So I'm their grandson.
So your mom is Grandpa's daughter!
Wait, then that makes me your mom's sister.
Crap! I don't want to touch this subject!
Here!
It's here!
Kaga
Family
Grave
The grave's wet.
That vase...
Masako-san had one too.
Ma...
Why'd she come here when she
didn't even show up to the funeral?
Rin, I'll be right back.
Huh?
Stay right here!
Pluck the weeds!
Okay!
What should I do?
Why'd she visit a grave with some guy?
Woof! Woof!
What is it? Why are you here?
I thought you were a stalker.
I'm just visiting the cemetery.
Seriously.
But I think you ought to know.
Rin's there.
She's at Grandpa's grave.
Umm, I...
To be honest, Rin's really important to me, so I don't think of you that much.
I don't know what's going on in your life.
Unless Rin wants to, I have no desire to let you two meet each other.
I already know that!
Did you follow me just to say that?
Do you want to look at Rin from afar?
We're going to clean up the grave,
light some incense and then go home.
That all might take some time though.
Anyway, Rin's waiting for me.
Just do what you want.
And we'll do what we want.
Sorry, Rin. Was I gone long?
Umm...
Are you okay? Sorry, I just had to go somewhere.
Sorry, was I gone long?
Not really.
Were you feeling lonely?
You're weird. Why are you so nervous?
I'm not weird.
Here.
Okay.
Put them over there.
Okay!
She's not a baby anymore.
Blood really does pass on.
You're right. She looks just like you, Ma-chan.
From back here, it's like...
She's really cute.
From back here, it's like she's with Souichi-san again.
I'm glad.
Whew, what a day.
Maybe these types of coincidences happen around the Bon Festival.
She's seven years old today.
Oh.
I was obviously surprised that you have a daughter,
but I was scared that he might be an ex-boyfriend.
Oh, please.
He has zero common sense.
Although I don't know what he'll be like in another fifty years.
Fifty years?
I guess it's safe to assume that guy is her boyfriend.
Hey, Daikichi.
I'm not saying it's wrong or anything...
Daikichi!
But for someone like her, she sure found a boyfriend quickly.
Daikichi, listen to me!
Right!
Can we visit Grandpa's house?
Isn't it close by?
I don't think that's Grandpa's house anymore.
Someone's living there?
No, no one's living there.
But it's my mom's older brother's house.
The family altar is there as well.
Oh...
Well, I'll ask my uncle if we can go into the backyard at least.
Really?!
Just the backyard, okay?
Okay!
I'll lead the way!
I'm going to continue with the new project.
Really?!
Are you sure, Ma-chan?
I'm alone because of my work.
I have to work more.
You already are!
You work more than almost anyone!
It's not enough.
I want to work so hard I can't
remember what I have for meals.
What do you mean? I always forget what I eat.
If I...
If I don't forget all those things...
I'll...
We're almost there!
Kaga
It hasn't changed!
No, but you have.
The bellflowers are gone!
So is the dirt!
Grandpa loved those bellflowers.
I don't think my uncle meant to remove them.
He knew they were Grandpa's favorite.
But because he had to remove them when winter came,
maybe he didn't know that they sprout again in the spring.
And these rocks are here to stop
weeds from growing all over the place.
We're lucky we moved Rin's fragrant olive in time.
But, we still have Grandpa's bellflowers at home, don't we?
They're fine then!
That's right!
I guess change isn't always bad.
That will always be Grandpa's grave, won't it?
Yeah!
Rin.
Yeah?
Happy birthday.
Happy Birthday,
Rin-chan
It's chocolate!
Saionji-sensei, could you look over it one last time?
Are you alright?
Maybe you took off more than you can chew this time.
I can't work when you say stuff like that, so please stop!
Go for it.
I promise I'll finish this.
Daikichi, the festival booths will close soon!
There's still time.
You're like Grandpa.
Kouki-kun's here!
What's up? Weren't we gonna meet you at the shrine?
My mom's too slow.
Where's your yukata?
I can't jump like this if I wear one!
Wasn't that awesome?
Where's your mom?
She said she'll meet us there once she gets her yukata on.
Let's go! The booths are gonna close!
Look out for cars, Daikichi!
I know!
Wait for me! It's hard to run in these shoes!
Then I'll carry you!
No way!
I wanna be carried!